Atlanta, GA, 30308 850-240-6650 ksexton.exe@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ksexton91 sxtnkyl.github.io/portfolio2020/ github.com/sxtnkyl

#### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Junior Software Developer with 2 years of self-guided, continuous growth-focused, coding experience and a focus on frontend and cloud services. Relatable industry skills from former Geologist career include client and team coordination, inner company cross-discipline coordination, and expansion of company services through research, acquisition, and application of new technologies.

#### **PROJECTS**

# URL SHORTENER 2020 // hiropes.info // github.com/sxtnkyl/url2020

- **Description** AWS powered tool for shortening URLs into six-character codes
- **Technical Focus** Understanding and building complex full-stack architectures with Node.js and AWS, functional integration of cloud services, security practices
- Solutions -
  - Cloudfront was chosen over simple S3 hosting to handle requests at edge locations, as well as handle caching and provide extra separation of http requests and cloud services
  - IAM policies were utilized to handle CORS across cloud services to assure internal services are restricted to only their designated functions
  - o HTTP-API was selected over REST API for custom domain support, simpler CORS integration
  - Lambda handlers were the best option as an abstraction layer to write or find data in DynamoDB
  - CloudWatch provided logs for troubleshooting and setting cost alarms to stop unforeseen costs
- **Tools** React, Node.js, AWS Cloud Services, CORS policy

#### TAILS WAG DOG TRAINING // tailswagatlanta.com // github.com/sxtnkyl/tailwag

- Description Client landing page for a local canine training business
- Technical Focus Customer engagement, Google Lighthouse Metrics, Versioning control
- Solutions -
  - Applied Material UI design documentation and theming to increase use engagement and ease of navigation, leading to more time spent on the webpage
  - Performed cross-browser CSS testing to improve UI/UX consistency
  - o Improved performance, accessibility, SEO, and best practices with Google Lighthouse Metrics
  - Maintained production and dev branches for version control, while client revisions and requests were integrated
- Tools React, Framer Motion, Material UI, Node.js, AWS Cloud Services

### POKEDEX 2020 // sxtnkyl.github.io/teambuilder // github.com/sxtnkyl/teambuilder

- **Description** Browser app for displaying tons of Pokémon data
- Technical Focus Expand skills with React hooks, API consumption, and animating components
- Solutions -
  - Redux was not a good use case due to project simplicity, but to gain familiarity, a Redux-style structure was implemented using React's useReducer and useContext hooks
  - Axios was chosen as the best use case for handling automatic JSON transformation for data returned from an external API, where the issue of limiting user fetch requests was solved by creating a debouncing hook
  - Proptype verification was implemented to aid with handling varying data types
- **Tools** React, Global State with useContext, useReducer, useCallback, API data fetching, Proptype Verification, React Spring, Material UI

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Proficient AWS Cloud Services, Node.js, CSS, JavaScript, React (Advanced Hooks), API Integration, Routing, React Animation Libraries
- Familiar Git, TypeScript, Relational and Non-Relational databases, CORS Integration, Form Handling
- Interested Golang, PWA, UX/UI Development Tools

### **EXPERIENCE**

# SELF-GUIDED EDUCATION // Software Engineer // OCTOBER 2018 - PRESENT

- Make a Plan Constructed a learning plan for full career path transition in less than 2 years
- Learn Fundamentals Completed Udemy JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Master class
- **Get Certified** Completed FreeCodeCamp curriculum for Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, and Front-End Libraries
- **Get Involved** Enrolled in local React ATL meetup group and 404 Tech Slack channel to ensure increase network and promote continuous personal growth through peer collaboration
- Make a Product Made from scratch and deployed an active client website

# JACOBS/CH2M // Geologist II // JULY 2017 - OCTOBER 2018

- Cost Efficiency Increased site visit efficiency by improving data collection logistics
- **Expand In-House Tools** Saved project cost by learning formerly subcontracted field work and office GIS services
- Flexibility Mentored new staff on field practices, collaborated with both public and private clients, contributed to both municipal and federal projects

## UNITED CONSULTING // Geologist I // AUGUST 2014 – JULY 2017

- **Client Relationship** Created lasting client relationship with City of Atlanta Department of Watershed by creating a reliable and reproducible method of delineating impacted roadway sub-surfaces and recommending appropriate, use-case, remedial actions
- **Go the Extra Mile** Improved historic record collection while conducting a GDOT subsurface investigation leading to discovery of additional site information critical to project success

#### **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA // Gainesville, FL // 2009-2013

- B.S. Geology Minor in Geographic Information Systems
- Field Researcher Data Collection and GIS Analyst 2012-2014